Guide to the New York Labor History Association Records WAG.198
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New York Labor History Association Records
1976-2018
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New York Labor History Association
Yellowitz, Irwin
LaTour, Jane
WAG.198
13.25 Linear Feet in 10 record cartons, 6 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, and 3 shared boxes.
1 videocassettes (vhs)
2 3.5" floppy disks
1 websites in one archived website.
1 electronic discs (cd-rom)
4 computer files in 2 5.25" floppy disks
New York Labor History Association (NYLHA) was founded in 1976 by trade unionists, academics, students, archivists, educators, labor editors, attorneys, and retirees, mostly from New York State. NYLHA encourages the study of workers and their organizations and serves as a bridge between past and present labor unionists and academics. This collection consists of materials created and collected by NYLHA documenting their actvities from the 1970s through the 2000s. Materials include correspondence, issues of the Work History News newsletter, conference recordings, electronic versions of documents, an archived version of the organization's website, and papers, photographs, programs, flyers, and other materials concerning NYLHA events.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions, but material pertaining to individual student papers may be restricted in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Please contact special.collections@nyu.edu with specific questions regarding access to such material.
Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Irwin Yellowitz sent a gift of five boxes of organization records of the New York Labor History Association, including approximately 100 photographs in 1998. The accession number associated with this gift is 1998.016.
In 2014 four conference recordings were found in the repository. The accession number associated with these materials is 2014.028.
In 2016 two additional donations from Jane LaTour added to the organization's records. The accessions numbers associated with these materials are 2016.038 and 2016.039.
In 2018 a proclamation declaring November 30, 1990 New York Labor History Association Day was donated by Joe Doyle; the accession number associated with this gift is 2018.126.
In June 2023, an accretion of administrative records was identified in the former NYLHA located on the 10th floor of Bobst Library; the accession number associated with this gift is 2023.050.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: Series I: Organizational Records; Series II: Special Events, Projects, and Publications
Historical Note
New York Labor History Association (NYLHA) was founded in 1976 by trade unionists, academics, students, archivists, educators, labor editors, attorneys, and retirees, mostly from New York State. NYLHA encourages the study of workers and their organizations and serves as a bridge between past and present labor unionists and academics.
Custodial History
The archived website was migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The link to California Digital Library was removed in October 2017.
Websites are selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials created and collected by NYLHA documenting their actvities from 1976 through 2018. Materials include correspondence, issues of the Work History News newsletter, conference recordings, an archived version of the organization's website, electronic files, and audiovisual materials, photographs, programs, flyers, and other materials concerning NYLHA events.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted.
Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information. If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials. If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu. Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Appraisal
Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored with the permission of the content owner. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://newyorklaborhistory.org/web/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
Labor -- History; Labor movement -- United States -- History; Labor unions -- United States -- History; Historians -- United States.; Yellowitz, Irwin; LaTour, Jane
- Series I: Organizational Records, 1976-2018; 5.5 Linear Feet in 5.5 record cartons
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists of executive board meeting agendas, minutes, member lists, reports, and mailings; dues, audits, budgets, invoices, and other financial documents; board president documents and correspondence; annual conference documents and news releases; and the organization constitution and by-laws.
  - Organizational Records, 1976-2016 (Box 1, Folder 1-56, Box 2, Folder 1-28, Box 3, Folder 1-42, Box 4, Folder 1-44, Box 5, Folder 1-32, Box 10, Folder 1-16)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 1983-1998 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
  - Presidency and Executive Board, 1998-2002 (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
  - Presidency and Executive Board, 2002-2005 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
  - Administrative Records -- General, 1996-2005 (Box 13, Folder 7--9)
  - Administrative Records -- General, 2001-2005 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Administrative Records, 2006-2012 (Box 13, Folder 11, Box 14, Folder 1-4)
  - Administrative Records -- General, 2016-2018 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Financial Records, 1997-2005 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Board Meetings, 1984-2004 (Box 14, Folder 7-9)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1991-1993 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Series II: Special Events, Projects, and Publications, 1976-2018; 5.5 Linear Feet in 4.5 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, and 3 shared boxes.; 1 websites; 1 videocassettes (vhs); 2 3.5" floppy disks; 4 computer files
  This series consists of documents, photographs, posters and broadsides pertaining to special events and projects, annual conferences, and organizational publications, such as Labor History Month, the John Commerford Award, the Barbara Wertheimer prize, film festivals, labor history tours, World History News, map projects, and occasional papers written by history students. This series also contains the organization's archived website and some unprocessed electronic records on physical carriers.
  - Special Events, Projects, and Publications, 1976-2016 (Box 6, Folder 1-44, Box 7, Folder 1-36, Box 8, Folder 1-24, Box 9, Folder 1-27, Box 10, Folder 17-27, Box 11, Folder 1-6, Box 12, Folder 1-4)
  - Labor History Month Poster, 2005-2012 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - May Conference -- Splits in the Labor Movement, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Newsletter, 1981-1994 (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
  - Newsletter, 1995-1996 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Newsletter, 1997-1999 (Box 15, Folder 6-7)
  - Newsletter, 1999-2005 (Box 15, Folder 8-10)
  - Newsletter, 2002-2008 (Box 15, Folder 11-12)
  - Newsletter, 2006-2007 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Newsletter, 2008-2009 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Newsletter, 2010-2012 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - News Service, 1990-2001 (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
  - News Service, 1992-2006 (Box 16, Folder 6-8)
  - Comerford Labor Education Award, 1998-2003 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Comerford Labor Education Award, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Comerford Labor Education Award, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Comerford Labor Education Award, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Comerford Labor Education Award, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Comerford Labor Education Award, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Comerford Labor Education Award, 2008 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Comerford Labor Education Award, 2009 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Comerford Labor Education Award, 2010 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Comerford Labor Education Award, 2011 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Comerford Labor Education Award, 2012 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Video: "Labor History Happened Here", 1999-05-22 (Box Shared Tamiment 015)
  - New York Labor History Association Day Proclamation, 1990-11-30 (Box Shared Tamiment 034, Folder 17)
  - Archived Website, May 1, 2009-ongoing
    Scope and Content Note
    The website includes news and event listings, labor history resources, and prize winners.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
    Accruals
    New site crawls are accrued semiannually.